Qin Army Supreme Commander Wang Qi
Zhao Army Supreme Commander Pang Nuan
General Wang Qi leads an army of 100,000 Qin troops.
Qin Army
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
王騎(おうき)将軍率いる秦国(しんこく)の軍勢10万
Zhao Army
対する
龐煖(ほうけん)に率いられた趙(ちょう)の軍勢12万
Versus the Zhao's 120,000 troops led by Pang Nuon.
The two armies encounter each other at Bayang.
両軍は 馬陽(ばよう)の地にて遭遇
The battlefield moved to a plain not far off from there, the Qian Plain,
そこから程近い広大な平野
乾原(かんげん)の地に戦場を移し
and they are now arriving at the moment of confrontation.
今 対決の時を迎えようとしていた
（信(しん)）ンンッ…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代の秦国
The setting is before the common era,
in the State of Qin during the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
The nameless boy Xin met with the young King Zheng,
名もなき少年 信は
若き王 政(せい)と出会い―
武功を上げて
ついに 百人隊の将にまでなった
distinguished himself in war, and finally become a Hundred-Man General.
Among those events, the neighboring State of Zhao suddenly invaded,
そんな中 突然 隣国の趙が攻め入り
未曽有の危機が訪れる
presenting an unprecedented crisis.
総大将 王騎は
いかなる戦いを仕掛けるのか
What kind of war will Supreme Commander Wang Qi wage?
And what kind of growth with Xin achieve?
そして
信は いかなる成長を遂げるのか
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
Seboo
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
G_I_A
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Birth of the Feixin Unit
（貂(てん)）すげえよ… すごいよ 蒙毅(もうき)！
Woah! This is incredible, Yi Meng!
わあ… ホントに
こんな数同士で戦うのか？
This many people are really gonna fight each other?
（蒙毅）ボ～ッとしてる暇はないよ
There's no room for spacing out.
今のうちに
戦場の様子をよく把握しておくんだ
Get a good grasp of the battlefield while we have the chance.
The Zhao Army's principal axis will be
趙軍の攻撃の主軸となるのは
あの３つの大隊からなる左軍６万だ
the three left units of 60,000 splitting off the main army.
State of Zhao General She Meng
State of Zhao General Wan Ji
State of Zhao General Gongsun Long
兵数 およそ２万の各大隊が―
With around 20,000 soldiers in each of those major units,
秦軍の本陣の
右脇腹を突こうと狙っている
they're aiming to pierce through the Qin Army's right flank.
それに対し 秦軍も
計４万の右軍が防御に当たっている
Against that, the Qin Army's right army, totaling 40,000, will play defense.
一方 秦の左軍と趙の右軍は
全軍から孤立した感がある
And I have a feeling that in the meantime, Qin's left army and Zhao's right army will separate from the rest of the armies.
That's while they're being surrounded by obstacles.
共に
障害物に取り囲まれているからね
（貂）…ということは 戦の勝敗は
So you're saying that victory and defeat
中央より右側の攻防に
懸かっているということか
will ride on the attacking and defense on the right side, rather than the center?
Exactly.
そのとおり　趙軍の主力は左軍６万
そして 秦軍の主力は―
The Zhao Army's main force is the 60,000 of the left army,
while the Qin Army's main force
副将 蒙武(もうぶ)率いる蒙武軍２万と
第１軍２万 計４万の中央軍だ
is the Meng Wu army of 20,000, led by Vice General Meng Wu, and 1st Army of 20,000,
adding up to a central army of 40,000.
Meng Wu...? Meng?
蒙武？“蒙”？
僕の父だ
（貂）ええっ！
My father.
So that is Meng Wu?
（李白(りはく)）あれが蒙武か
Son of Qin's White Elder, Meng Ao,
State of Zhao General Li Bai
（李白）秦の〝白老〞
蒙驁(もうごう)の子にして
that man is Lü Buwei's most trusted general, Meng Wu.
あの呂氏(りょし)が 最も
信頼を寄せる武将 蒙武
According to rumors, his offensive power is something to be reckoned with.
（剛乱(ごうらん)）ウワサでは
ヤツの攻撃力は相当のものとか
Gang Luan?
剛乱か
Fight fire with fire.
（剛乱）
力には力　どうか 李白さま
What do you think, Lord Li Bai?
Entrust the front-most line to us, the heavily armored mounted unit.
最前線は
我ら重装騎兵隊に お任せを
So the Zhao Army wants it to be a test of strength, eh?
（王騎）趙軍は力比べと来ましたか
（王騎）
さあ 見せていただきましょう
あなたの力を
Well then, go ahead and show me your power...
（蒙武）ンンッ！ 突撃！
Charge!
い… 行った！
Th-They're going!
It-It's begun!
（尾平(びへい)）は… 始まった！
（剛乱）殺せー！
Kill them!
Meng Yi, is your father gonna be all right?!
蒙毅 お前の親父(おやじ)さん 大丈夫か？
（蒙毅）甘く見すぎだ
They've taken him too lightly.
砕け散れ 蒙武！
I'll crush you, Meng Wu!
（殴る音）
（剛乱）ウワッ！
This is the power of the military commander known as Meng Wu.
（蒙毅）
これが 蒙武という武将の力だ
（趙兵たち）ウワッ！
Incredible!
（兵士）すげえ… バケモノだ
（信）あの野郎…
He's a monster!
Th... That bastard...
General Meng Wu!
（兵士たち）蒙武将軍！
あっ！
蒙武将軍が 一気に流れをつかんだ
General Meng Wu took control of the flow in an instant!
Maybe if he keeps this up...
ひょっとして このまま…
いや
趙の先鋒隊も黙っては いないよ
No.
Zhao's vanguard will not stay quiet, either.
趙の左軍には 渉孟(しょうもう)将軍がいる
And General She Meng is in Zhao's left army.
Here they come!
来るぞ！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（なぎ払う音）
（兵士たち）ウワッ！
なに！
（尾平）あっ！ 右軍が！
What?!
The right army!
The vanguards are evenly matched.
（沛浪(はいろう)）先鋒隊は互角だな
（田有(でんゆう)）ああ
Yeah.
Dammit! Are we still gonna have to wait for our turn?!
くそ… 俺たちの出番は まだかよ
（副官）李白さま
蒙武の勢いが止まりません
Lord Li Bai, Meng Wu's momentum is not stopping.
重歩兵は 斜めに陣を構え
左翼に弓兵500を展開
Have the heavy infantry move diagonally to take position
and deploy 500 bowmen on the left wing.
そろそろか
It should be soon, yes?
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）
はっ… まだ知らせは入りませぬが
Yes. No information has come in yet.
（昌文君）本日には王騎将軍率いる
我が軍が 趙軍と接触するはずです
But our army led by Wang Qi should make contact with the Zhao Army today.
General Wang Qi...
王騎将軍…
歯がゆいですか？
Frustrated, my king?
ああ　かなうことなら この目で
事の成り行きをつぶさに見届けたい
Yes.
If I could have my wish, I would like to see course of events play out in detail with my own eyes.
だが―
But...
俺は
ここで こうして座っているだけだ
All I can do is sit here.
肝心の戦は
将軍たちに任せるしかない
I have no choice but to leave the all-important war to the generals.
That is what a king is, I suppose.
王とは そういうものなのだろう
（昌文君）御意
Yes, my king.
あっ… 蒙武軍の勢いが
弱まってきたように見える
The momentum of Meng Wu Army looks like it's weakening.
This is Zhao's defensive unit strategy.
趙の守備隊の策だ
They're firing from only one side
片側からのみの射撃と
歩兵に 斜めの陣を取らせ―
and having the foot soldiers take a diagonal formation
thus parrying the mounted unit's momentum.
騎馬隊の勢いをいなしているんだ
Meng Wu's power is greater than the rumors indicated,
（趙荘(ちょうそう)）蒙武の力はウワサ以上だな
State of Zhao Strategist Zhao Zhuang
（趙荘）
だが単純な武力だけでは
李白は抜けぬ
but military might alone will not allow him to make it past Li Bai.
So, what will you do now, Wang Qi?
さあ ここから どうする？ 王騎よ
右軍 中央軍ともに 手はずどおり
The right and central armies have gone according to plan.
All that's left is the most important element, the left army, is it?
あとは 肝心要の左軍 …ですか
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）中央軍と右軍が
激戦を繰り広げる中
As a fierce battle unfolded with the central and right army,
秦国左軍には まだ
何の号令も かかってはいなかった
the State of Qin left army had still not received any orders.
State of Qin Thousand-Man General Bi
（壁(へき)）ンンッ…
Is there any meaning in protecting this location with such perilous terrain?
地形の険しいこの場所を
守る意味などあるのか？
それよりも 中央軍を
援護に行くべきではないのか…
Wouldn't it be more useful for us to go support the central army?
（干央(かんおう)）壁千人将
（壁）ハッ…
Thousand-Man General Bi!
Understand that the cornerstone to our army's attack does not lie with the central army,
（干央）
我が軍の攻めの要は
中央軍にあらず
State of Qin Army Combat Commander Gan Yang
この左軍と心得よ
it is with us, the left army.
はぁ？ この左軍が攻めの要とは？
This left army is the cornerstone to our attack?
この地からは 敵本陣も目指せず
中央を狙うにしても出遅れています
From this location, not only can we not target the enemy's headquarters,
it's also too late to target the central army.
戦は まだ始まったばかりである
The war has only just begun.
いきなり本陣など狙っても届かぬ
（壁）しかし…
Any attacks on the headquarters now would not reach it.
But!
I have a plan given to me by General Wang Qi.
王騎将軍より授けられた策がある
ハッ… 王騎将軍の策と？
General Wang Qi's plan?
It will turn into a severe battle,
苛烈な戦いとなろうが この干央
死闘は 最も得意とするところ
but I, Gan Yang, am most skilled at struggles to the death.
The left army's charge has begun.
（騰(とう)）左軍 進撃を開始しました
（王騎）ンフフフッ…
これで準備は整いました
Then all preparations are in order.
It is about time "to shoot the arrow", I suppose.
そろそろ“矢”を射る時ですかねえ
ここは しばらく頼みましたよ
（騰）はっ！
I'll leave this place to you for a bit.
Yes, sir.
アア… 左軍が突撃した
The left army charged!
ヘヘッ… どうやら
ようやく 俺たちの出番のようだな
Looks like it's finally gonna be our time to shine.
そうだろう？
Ain't that right?
（馬のいななき）
王騎将軍！
General Wang Qi!
It's General Wang Qi!
（兵士）王騎将軍だ…
（兵士）王騎将軍…
General Wang Qi...
（兵士たち）
王騎将軍… 王騎将軍…
ご覧のとおり 今し方 左軍１万が
趙右軍２万に攻撃を開始しました
As you can see,
a moment ago the left army of 10,000 charged on the Zhao right army of 20,000.
10,000 versus...
１万対…
（尾到(びとう)）２万…
20,000?
実は この戦いが
序盤戦で 最も重要な戦いです
The truth of the matter is,
in this fight, the opening phase is the most important.
ンフフフッ… 童 信 いよいよ
修行の成果を見せる時ですよ
Youngster Xin, it's finally time for you to show off the fruits of your training.
任せとけ！
Just leave it to me!
どうやら
臆するところはなさそうですね
Somehow, you seem to be without hesitation.
よろしい
では この隊に任務を授けましょう
Very well, I'll now explain this unit's mission.
戦を効率よく進めるためには―
In order for a war to progress efficiently,
it is an ironclad rule that you must capture land that gives one an advantage in fighting.
有利に戦える地を
奪うことが定石です
But there is another good way besides that.
しかし
それ以外にも よい方法があります
And that is to kill the enemy's skilled military commanders.
敵の有能な武将を
殺していくことです
The general currently leading the Zhao right army of 20,000, known as Feng Ji,
State of Zhao General Feng Ji
（王騎）
今 趙右軍２万を
率いている
馮忌(ふうき)という将軍は
戦局分析に
非常に長(た)けた人物です
is exceedingly proficient at analyzing the state of war.
The closer you get to the climax of the battle, the more those sorts of military generals
そういう武将は
戦いが佳境になればなるほど―
やっかいな存在となります
become a troublesome existence.
And so, first we'll need to get rid of that Feng Ji, won't we?
…というわけで まずは その馮忌に
消えていただきましょうか
Youngster Xin,
童 信
（信）ハッ…
it's your time to shine as a Hundred-Man General.
あなたの百人隊の出番です
どさくさに紛れて
馮忌の首を取ってきてください
Please slip into the confusion and take Feng Ji's head.
Feng Ji's... head!
（信）馮忌の首…
ンフフフッ… これは
とても重要な任務ですよ 童 信
This is an extremely important mission, Youngster Xin.
できますか？
Can you do it?
あの無国籍地帯での修行を通じて
気づいたことがある
There's something I realized during my training in that stateless area.
何千何万という大軍勢の戦いの中で
In a huge battle of tens of thousands of soldiers
one hundred men are truly just a speck in the big picture.
100人って数は 正に豆粒で
小さい存在だ　だが―
But a speck has the kind of strength a speck has!
豆粒には 豆粒なりの強さがある
隙間を抜く身軽さがあり結集すれば
決して砕けねえ石にもなる
It has nimbleness of slipping through gaps,
and when it concentrates, it becomes a stone that will never break!
This Hundred-Man Unit accepts that mission!
その任務
この百人隊が引き受けた！
ンフッ… 繰り返しますが
これは大事な一戦です
Let me just say this again, this is a very important battle.
If by some chance you fail, it will not be tolerated.
万が一にも 失敗は許しません
I hope I can count on you, Hundred-Man General Xin.
よろしく頼みましたよ 百人将 信
ンフフフッ… 安心しましたよ
ちゃんと成長しているようですね
I'm relieved.
It seems you really are growing.
Very well, I will give you a reward.
よろしい　では褒美をひとつ
Feixin Unit.
( Feixin - Flying Xin (Faith) )
“飛信(ひしん)隊”
この名をあなたの隊に与えます
I am giving your unit that name.
Fei
xin
Unit
Feixin Unit
飛信隊…
Feixin Unit...!
（蒙毅）ムダだよ
You're wasting your time.
この大軍勢の中から
信たちを見つけるのはムリだ
In such a huge army, there's no chance you'll be able to stop Xin.
それは…
That's...
あっ！ あそこから出てくる連中が
ほら 茂みのほうに！
Those guys coming from over there!
Look! At the thicket!
Yeah, it is! That's Xin!
あれ そうだよ！ 信だ！
（渕(えん)）作戦を立てましょう 信どの
Let's form a plan, Lord Xin.
I'll start by explaining the situation, so please listen closely.
（渕）状況から説明しますから
よく聞いてください
標的の馮忌が率いる趙右軍２万は
秦左軍１万と交戦中
Our target, Feng Ji, is leading the right Zhao army of 20,000 and is currently engaged with the left Qin army of 10,000.
趙軍の注意は 完全に
正面の秦軍に向いているでしょう
The Zhao Army's attention is sure to be wholly focused on the Qin Army in front of them.
そこにです
That's where we come in.
We will cut into the enemy from the side.
側面から回り込んだ我らが突入
Our plan is to attack the enemy where they're unguarded and make a push straight towards the headquarters.
敵の虚をつき 一気に
本陣まで迫るという段取りです
Attack where they're open?
虚をついたからって
そんなに うまくいくんスか？
Do you think that'll work?
I have not done it with an army,
（渕）軍相手というわけではないが
似たような経験は何度かある
but I have had similar experiences many times.
だが この作戦には
その前段階として大きな問題がある
But there is a big problem with this plan in regards to that first step.
敵に見つからずに―
It depends on us moving to our point of entry, which is directly beside the enemy, without being seen.
突入口である真横まで
移動ができるかどうかだ
It'll be okay.
大丈夫だ　そこは逆に
百人隊っていう小ささが武器になる
For that part, the smallness of a Hundred-Man Unit is actually a weapon.
（王騎）ご苦労でした 騰
戦況は どうですか？
Well done, Teng.
How goes the battle?
はっ…
右軍は だいぶ押し込まれました
Sir. The right army has largely been pushed back.
中央の蒙武軍は 李白の守備の前に
勢いを失ったままです
The central Meng Wu Army is losing momentum against Li Bai's defense.
左軍は どうです？
（騰）左軍は…
What about the left army?
The left is...
善戦しています
fighting a good fight.
第４軍の将 干央のおかげで
士気は上がっています
Thanks to the Fourth Army's general, Gan Yang,
the soldiers' morale has been raised.
However... It's in quite a precarious position, that left army.
…とはいえ 危ういですねえ 左軍は
So then, it is indeed to entice Feng Ji, sir?
やはり 馮忌の誘い込みですか
（王騎）早々に“矢”が届かねば
左軍は 大変な目に遭いそうです
Unless the "arrow" reaches its target soon, the left army will be facing quite some peril.
We'll be right next to them pretty soon.
そろそろ真横だろう
（山和(さんか)）うまくいったな
It went off without a hitch.
Tell the back,
後ろに伝えろ　もうすぐ突撃だ
心の準備しとけってな
"We're going to charge soon. Ready your hearts and minds."
（田有）おう
Right.
Vermin...
ネズミが
（信）ンンッ…
茂みが低くなってきやがった
Damn, the thicket is thinning out.
Stop, Feixin Unit!
止まれ 飛信隊
All right!
よ～し ドンピシャ真横だ
We're directly to the side of them!
Forward! Forward!
進め進め！ 敵は ひるんでいるぞ！
The enemy is faltering!
All right!
よっしゃ！ 秦軍が押してっぞ！
The Qin Army is pushing forward!
Half of the left army's momentum is actual ability.
（王騎）左軍の勢いの半分は実力
そして もう半分は―
And the other half
is the Zhao Army general Feng Ji's trap.
趙の将軍 馮忌のワナです
（馮忌）前線を下げろ
黒離(こくり) 黒霊(こくれい)の重装歩兵を前に
Move the front line back.
Have Hei Li and Hei Ling's heavy armored units move forward.
両翼も配置に就け
Deploy both wings.
（伝令）呉方(ごほう)隊 退却しろ！
呉英(ごえい)隊も続け！
Wu Fang Unit, retreat!
全軍 退却だ！
（兵士）あいつら逃げたぞ！
Wu Ying Unit, as well!
Ah, they're running away!
All units, retreat!
前線が ひいた？ 何だ？
The front line drew back...
Why?
確かに押しては いたが
そこまでの手ごたえはなかったぞ
It's true we're pushing them, but they shouldn't react to that extent.
Could it be...
ひょっとして…
After 'em! Kill 'em!
ウオーッ！ 追え！ 殺せ！
壁隊 止まれ！ 敵のワナかもしれぬ
各伍(ご)は その場に停止だ！
Bi Unit, stop!
This could be an enemy trap!
All Wu, halt where you are!
Follow 'em!
（兵士）ウオーッ！ 追え！
（重歩兵隊長１）
来おったな 勘違いした素人どもが
So they're coming?
You amateurs have made a mistake.
Everyone, it is time for a slaughter!
皆の者 殺戮(さつりく)の時だ
（兵士）ま… 待て！
W-Wait!
Stop! Stop!
止まれ！ 止まれー！
Lord Bi! The right!
（北朱）あっ！ 壁さま 右を！
（壁）ハッ…
Oh no!
ハッ… マズイ！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
馮忌のワナが ついに動いた
Feng Ji's trap has finally been sprung,
the spears of the heavily-armed soldiers and the arrows that pour down like rain.
重歩兵の槍(やり)と雨のごとく降り注ぐ矢
Against that fierce attack,
その猛攻により
左軍兵士の半数近くが倒れ
nearly half of the left army soldiers fell.
And many foot soldiers fled out of their own personal safety.
多くの歩兵が
我先にと逃げ出すありさまであった
Shit... Shit!
くそ… くそ！
（田有）ひ… ひでえ
Th-That's awful.
マズイぞ 信どの…
This is bad, Lord Xin.
全員の士気が高くなければ
集の強さなど発揮できない
Unless everyone's morale is high,
we won't be able to wield the power of a concentrated unit.
飛信隊 隊形を組むぞ
Feixin Unit! Let's get in battle formation!
100人で 万の大将の所まで行くには
余計な戦いは してらんねえ
In order for a hundred men to get to a great general of 10,000, you can't have any unnecessary battles.
だから この縦長の隊形で
敵将目がけて一直線に突っ走る
That's why we're going to be in this oblong formation
and heading in a straight line for the enemy general.
The big problem will be the moment we break into them.
問題は突入の瞬間だ
Pretty soon, we can expect the enemy to realize we're here and start defending.
こっから先は さすがに
敵も気づいて 守りやがるからな
防御をぶっ飛ばして
突破口を開くために―
In order to blast through their defenses and make an entrance for ourselves,
先頭には ４人の怪力伍長を並べる
at the helm will be the four most superhumanly strong Wuchang.
Zhong Tie, Shan He, Tian You,
中鉄(ちゅうてつ)！ 山和！ 田有！
そして 第16伍長の竜川(りゅうせん)
and Wuchang of the 16th Wu, Long Chuan!
Long Chuan
Long Chuan. I know this is your first time, but I've got high expectations for you!
竜川 あんたとは
初めてだが期待してるぜ
Like Tian You said,
田有が言ってた
馬鹿力(ばかぢから)は自分の２人分はあるってな
"You have the animal strength of two people."
（田有）竜川
Long Chuan!
何だ？ お前　まさか
おじけづいてんじゃねえだろうな？
What's going on, man?
Don't tell me you're getting cold feet?
（尾平たち）えっ？
（松左(しょうさ)）ムリもねえ
You can't blame him.
Song Zuo
（松左）先月
子供が生まれたんだとさ
His child was born last month.
And it's his firstborn.
初めての子供だ
察してやんなよ　ここで死にゃ
かわいいガキの顔は見られねえ
Try to understand, if he dies here, he'll never be able to see that cute kid's face again.
Let's get back on topic.
話を戻すぞ
俺たち飛信隊は いわば１本の矢だ
We, the Feixin Unit are like a single arrow.
If we can fly to that enemy general, we can take his head.
敵将の所まで飛んできゃ
その首取れるし
届かなきゃ そこで たたき折られて
全員 死ぬ
But if we break there, everyone dies.
And if we fail,
そして 俺らが失敗したら―
the left army in front of us will all die as well.
目の前でやられてる左軍のヤツらも
全員 死ぬ
And all of the people back at the village waiting for you will die!
お前らの帰りを待ってる村の人間も
全員 死ぬんだ！
Did you forget?!
忘れたのか！ この戦いに負けりゃ
趙軍は秦国内に なだれ込んでくる
If we lose this battle, the Zhao Army will surge into Qin borders!
そしたら 馬央(ばおう)みてえに
そこら中で虐殺が起こるんだ！
And if that happens, there could be a huge slaughter like there was at Mayang!
Those guys are serious!
ヤツらはマジだ！
Long Chuan!
竜川！
If we don't win, your kid will be killed!
勝たなきゃ
お前のガキも殺されるんだ！
Drill that into your skulls!
お前ら 頭に たたき込んどけ
That's the kind of battle this is!
これは そういう戦いなんだ！
Let's go, captain.
行こう 隊長
おいらたちで
まずひとつ 勝ちをつかみ取ろう
Let's get our first victory together.
（重歩兵）敵襲！ 左方 敵襲！
Enemy attack!
Enemy attack from the left!
チッ！ もう気づかれた
They noticed us already?!
It doesn't matter! The only place we can go is forward!
関係ねえ！ あとは行くだけだ！
（重歩兵隊長２）
重歩兵 前へ！ 壁を築け！
Heavy soldiers, forward!
Form a wall!
Shit!
くそ！
竜川！
Long Chuan!
Long Chuan, wait! You're going too far by yourself!
竜川 待て！ １人で出すぎだ！
竜川 お前 まさか…
Long Chuan!
You're not going to...?!
Tian You...
田有さん
あんた ひとつ思い違いをしてるよ
You were wrong about one thing.
My animal strength
おいらの馬鹿力は…
（重歩兵たち）ウワッ！
（竜川）あんたの３人分だ！
is that of three men!
You really brought someone great along, Tian You!
すげえヤツ連れてきたな 田有
Let's go, guys!
行くぞ おら！ 飛信隊 突撃だ！
Feixin Unit, charge!
（重歩兵）両側から挟み込め！
Attack them from both sides!
Divide them and break them to pieces!
分断して細切れにしろ！
They're closing in on us!
（兵士）
詰められるぞ！ もっと急げ！
Faster!
At this speed, the path we opened is gonna close!
（兵士）この速さじゃ
開いた道が閉じちまうぜ！
Go!
いけ！ 崇原(すうげん)伍人衆！
Chong Wan Wu members!
Chong Wan
Bastard!
野郎 優男のくせに やるじゃねえか
For such a dainty-lookin' guy he's pretty good!
And the other guys in his Wu are pretty strong, too!
しかも 伍のヤツらまで強(つえ)えぞ！
（尾平）よっしゃ！ 行け！
Okay, let's go!
ヒイッ…
Don't retreat! That's the enemy's trap!
下がるな！ 敵のワナだ
Even if you retreat, everyone will just be killed!
下がっても皆殺しに遭う
活路は前だ！
Our path to survival is forward!
Thousand-Man General Bi.
壁千人将…
（兵士）千人将…
Thousand-Man General...
Our path to survival is forward?
活路は前？
That's right!
そうだ　前にいる趙兵の所まで
行けば 矢は もう降ってこぬ
If we make it to the Zhao soldiers in front of us,
the arrows will stop falling!
We need to gather people together and break through!
兵力を集めて 突破するんだ！
（兵士）なるほど
I get it!
孫(そん)百人隊 集まれ！
（兵士）郭(かく)隊もだ！
Sun Hundred-Man Unit, gather!
Guo Unit, too!
Commander Gan Yang!
干央軍長… 敵本陣を突く気だ
He's trying to pierce through the enemy formation!
壁隊 前進！ 軍長に続け！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
Bi Unit, forward!
Follow the commander!
（副官）馮忌さま
正面に前進してくる部隊があります
Lord Feng Ji!
There's advancing towards us head-on!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）馮忌に動揺はなかった
Feng Ji was not shaken.
Currently, there were only about 1,500 in the center that showed themselves to be advancing.
実際のところ 前進を見せたのは
中央の およそ1,500だけである
それ以外は背を見せて敗走していた
The rest were showing their backs and retreating.
まずは 予定どおり
掃討隊3,000を繰り出し これを討つ
First, he sent out a clean-up unit of 3,000 as he had planned to combat it.
With that, the Qin left army would in essence be destroyed.
これで 実質
秦左軍は壊滅することになる
Then all that remained were the 1,500 enemy soldiers.
あとは
前進してきた1,500の敵兵のみ
Of course, that was not a difficult enemy to overcome.
もちろん難しい敵ではない
But here, the aesthetics of Feng Ji's war is made to show its face.
だが ここで馮忌の戦の美学が
顔をのぞかせる
How to leave out the unnecessary,
いかに ムダを省き
いかに 効率よく敵を討つか
and find the most efficient way to attack the enemy?
For a brief period, Feng Ji's mind was searching for a way too cook the remaining 1,500 soldiers.
しばし 馮忌の思考は―
残兵1,500の
料理のしかたを模索した
Therefore, that consciousness was not able to grasp
故に その意識は捉えていなかった
横から迫る飛信隊の存在を
the existence of the Feixin Unit attacking from the side.
（伝令）急報！ 左方より敵襲！
その数100人　既に２陣まで進行中
Emergency report!
An enemy attack from the left!
It's about 100 men!
They've already progressed to the second formation!
（副官）２陣？ ほかに敵影は？
Second formation?!
Are there signs of any other enemies?
ありません
百人隊の単独行動のようです
There are not.
A Hundred-Man Unit seems to be acting on its own.
百人隊 単独？ どういうことだ…
A Hundred-Man Unit alone?
What do you mean?
I see.
そうか
So that's what it is...?
そういうことか
Wang Qi,
王騎 貴様のねらいは俺の首
your target is my head?
面白い　取れるものなら取ってみろ
Interesting. If you think you can get it, go ahead and try!
ンフッ…
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
The unit is... getting separated?!
（信）隊を分離する？
For the sake of victory...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
勝利のために 信 進むべき道は前だ
Xin, the way for you to move is forward!
Wang Qi's
Flying Arrow
Next time,
次回 “王騎の飛矢”
End
Wang Qi's
Flying Arrow